Guide to the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera 1700-1990 PR 31
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: LOOSE EPHEMERA
  - Subseries I: SMALL EPHEMERA
    - Furniture (Offsite-box 57)
      Hammocks (see: HOUSEHOLD, Cord and twine)
      Iron, wire, and metal furniture
      Looking glasses, picture frames, mirrors (some from BCL vol. 20)
      Mechanical and folding furniture (see also: DRUGS AND MEDICINES, Health chairs)
      Mosquito canopies
      Office furniture
    - Hardware (Offsite-box 58)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 07-07A
      Foundries and iron works
      Grinders and polishers
      Locks and alarms
      Machines, miscellaneous
      Manufacturers, miscellaneous
      Mathematical instruments
      Merchants (New York City, New York State, miscellaneous)
      Mining (minerals, stock certificates, miscellaneous)
    - Hardware (Offsite-box 59)
      Nails and screws
      Pumps
      Safes
      Sanders
      Saws, rasps, lathes, and planes
      Scales (Fairbanks, miscellaneous)
      Sheet and plated metals
      Steam engines
      Street cleaners and graders
      Tools
      Water filters
      Water pumps (see: WATERWORKS)
      Wire cloth and screening
      Wire rope
    - Hardware (Offsite-box 60)
      War materials production "Army Navy E Program:"
      Award booklets
      Correspondence
    - Hotels and Restaurants (Offsite-box 61)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 07 B-G, arranged geographically (those beginning with "Hotel" are filed by their second word)
      Hotels:
      Connecticut
      Massachusetts
      New Hampshire
      New Jersey
      New York City Hotels:
      American
      Astor
      Coney Island
      Cranston's
      Earle's
      Fifth Avenue
      McAlpin
      Manhattan Beach
      New Yorker
      Plaza
      Rathbun's
      St. Nicholas
      St. Regis
      Waldorf Astoria
    - Hotels and Restaurants (Offsite-box 62)
      New York City Restaurants:
      A-Z restaurants
    - Hotels and Restaurants (Offsite-box 63)
      New York State Restaurants:
      Adirondack Mountains
      Albany and Troy
      Buffalo and Niagara Falls
      Catskill Mountains
      Long Island
      Utica
      Pennsylvania Restaurants
      American restaurants by geographic region:
      East coast Restaurants
      Midwest Restaruants
      Southern Restaurants
      West coast Restaruants
    - Household (Offsite-box 64)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 08-09 A-B
      Cleansers:
      Sapolio (automobile ads, booklets, carriage ads, outdoor ads, shop ads and displays, trade cards, miscellaneous)
      Miscellaneous cleanser brands
      Cleaning equipment (mops, brooms, brushes, etc.)
      Cleaning services
      Cord, rope, and twine
    - Household (Offsite-box 65)
      Carpet cleaners
      Carpet sweepers
      Carpet vacuums
      Carpets and floor cloths
      Paper carpet, matting and linoleum
      Glues and cements (Major's Cement, miscellaneous)
      House furnishings:
      Appliances, electric
      China manufacturers
      Churns
      Containers
      Cookware
      Furniture (see: FURNITURE)
      Glass and china merchants (Eighteenth, nineteenth and twentieth centuries)
      Glass jars and bottles
      Glass manufacturers
      Ice cream freezers
    - Household (Offsite-box 66)
      Linens
      Refrigerators
      Silver and cutlery
      Stoneware
      Miscellaneous furnishings Ice companies
      Insecticides (see: AGRICULTURE)
      Laundry:
      Bluing/bleach
      Clothes drying
      Clothes washing tubs and boards
      Clothes washing machines
      Clothes wringers
      Dyes and dye works
      Irons and ironing
      Laundries and cleaners
    - Household (Offsite-box 67)
      Laundry Soap:
      Babbitt
      David's
      Ivorine Pearline
      Kendall brands
      Kendall Soapine
      Lautz
      Lavine
      Sapolio (see: Cleansers)
      Three Ball
      Tulip Laundry Starch
    - Household (Offsite-box 68)
      Lighting
      Candles
      Gas companies
      Gas meters
      Lamps (Electric, Gas, Oil and Fluid, Street)
      Matches
      Mirrors and picture frames (see: FURNITURE, Looking glasses and picture frames)
      Polishes
      Stove (Dixon's, Rising Sun, miscellaneous)
      Shades and blinds (see also: BUILDING, Awnings and shades)
    - Insurance (Offsite-box 69)
      (inc. material from BCL scrapbooks 09 C-E) Accident/casualty
      Agents and brokers
      Automobile
      Fire:
      New York Bowery
      Niagara
      North American
      Miscellaneous Fire escapes
      Firemen and fire companies
      General:
      Aetna
      Continental
      German American
      Germania Glen's Falls
      Hartford
      Home
      Liverpool & London & Globe
      Phenix
      Phoenix
      Providence Washington
    - Insurance (Offsite-box 70)
      General, con't
      Prudential
      Stuyvesant
      Travelers
      Miscellaneous Life
      Metropolitan
      Mutual Life of New York
      New York Life
      Provident Mutual
      Southern Life
    - Jewelry (Offsite-box 71, Offsite-box 71-A, Offsite-box 71-B)
      including material from BCL scrapbooks 09 F-G
      Celluloid, tortoise, ivory, etc.
      Clocks and watches
      Gold and silver beaters
      Jewelers (18th, 19th and 20th century, including Tiffany companies)
    - Leather Goods (Offsite-box 72)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 10
      Saddles
      Tanners and leather manufacturers
      Trunks and cases
    - Military (Offsite-box 72)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 10-1/2
      Civil War, 1861-1865
      Spanish-American War, 1898
      World War I, 1914-1918
      World War II, 1939-1945
      Bonds and war effort
      Charity and relief work
      Education
      Rallies and entertainment
      Rationing
    - Military (Offsite-box 73)
      Korean War, 1950-1953
      Persian Gulf War, 1991
      Flags
      Veterans' services
    - Oil (Offsite-box 73)
      including material from BCL scrapbook 10A
      Illuminating and radiant (Pratt, miscellaneous companies)
      Lubricating and machine
      Oil company stock certificates
    - Optical (Offsite-box 73)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 10 A-1/2
      New York City merchants and manufacturers
      National merchants and manufacturers
    - Paper (Offsite-box 74)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 11 B
      Manufacturers A-Z
      Orr Company
      Embossed pieces
    - Periodicals (Offsite-box 75)
      includescmaterial from BCL scrapbooks 11 & 11A
      Magazines
      National titles A-Z
      Frank Leslie
      Godey's
      Life
      Mast, Crowell & Kirkpatrick
      Progress
      Puck
      Scientific American
      Scribner's
      Youth's Companion Newspapers
      National papers A-Z
      New York City papers
      Daily News
      New York Observer
      New York Recorder
      New York Times
      New York Tribune
      North Side News
      Sun
      Miscellaneous papers Subscription houses and dealers
      Subscription receipts
    - Photography (Offsite-box 76)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 11C
      Camera clubs
      Camera obscura
      Photograph albums and exhibitions
      Photograph colorists, restorers, etc.
      Photographers:
      National
      California
      New York State
      Photographers in New York City:
      A-Z miscellaneous
      Bogardus
      Brady
      Fredricks
      Gurney
      Lawrence
      Robinson
      Rockwood
      Sarony
      Photographic equipment and suppliers
      Cameras, projectors, etc.
      Miscellaneous material
    - Printing and Engraving (Offsite-box 77)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 13 & 13 A-B
      Embossers
      Engravers, wood engravers, and die cutters
      Equipment
      Ink
      Ault & Wilborg Co.
      Presses
      Hoe & Co.
      Rollers
      Label printers
      Crumb Label Co.
      Druggists and chemists Miscellaneous
    - Printing and Engraving (Offsite-box 78)
      Printers and Engravers
      A-S miscellaneous
    - Printing and Engraving (Offsite-box 79)
      T-Z miscellaneous
      American Bank Note Company
      American Photo-Lithographic Company
      Bufford's Sons
      Calvert Lithographing and Engraving Company
      Currier and Ives
      Donaldson Brothers
      Donnelley and Sons
      Ketterlinus Printing House
      King & Baird
      Knight and Howland
      Major and Knapp
      Maverick
      Prang and Company
      Strobridge Lithographing Company
    - Printing and Engraving (Offsite-box 80)
      Calendars
      1896-1909
    - Printing and Engraving (Offsite-box 81)
      1910-1912
      Bullock Electric
      H & S. Pogue Co.
      Miscellaneous (advertising for calendars) Printing for the blind
      Stencil makers
      Type and typography
      Keystone Type Foundry
    - Professions and Occupations (Offsite-box 82)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 14
      Decorators
      Dentistry
      Dentists
      Equipment and supplies
      Clairvoyants
      Doctors
      Lectures
      Schools and training
      Treatments
      Stenographers
      Veterinary
    - Professions and Occupations (Offsite-box 83)
      Miscellaneous Professions
      Advertisements
      Business Cards (attorneys, etc.)
      Licenses
      Receipts
    - Publications (Offsite-box 84)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 12 & 12 A-B
      Bookbinders
      Booksellers
      Rare and Used Booksellers, auctions, etc.
      Publishers and booksellers
      Harper & Brothers
      Harper, Francis B.
    - Real Estate (Offsite-box 85)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 14 A
      Auctions
      Deeds and indentures
      Emigrant lands and agents
      Office buildings (New York City)
      Real Estate Board of New York
      Rentals
      Subdivisions
      Taxes and assessments
      Titles and abstracts
    - Religion, Philanthropy, and Hospitals (Offsite-box 86)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 14 B
      Hospitals and asylums
      Philanthropy
      Charity organizations
      Orphanages/children's aid
      Relief efforts
      Miscellaneous Religion
      American Bible Society
      Benefit events/donation visits
      Calling cards
      Churches
      Concerts and musical events
      Consecrations, inductions, and memorials
      Evangelists
      Jewish/Hebrew material
      Missions/missionaries
      Public programs
      Publications and prospectuses
      Socials, picnics, and outings
      Sunday schools
    - Rubber (Offsite-box 86)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 14-1/2
    - Schools and Colleges (Offsite-box 87)
      Academies, seminaries, and institutes
      Professional schools
      Eastman College/Eastman Business School
      Shorthand training
      Penmanship exercises and booklets
      Public schools
      Rewards of merit
      Tuition receipts
      Universities and colleges
    - Seeds and Plants (Offsite-box 88)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 14 D
      Florists and flower shows
      Nurseries and seed companies (billheads, invoices, catalog pages and plates)
      Seed packets
    - Sewing Machines (Offsite-box 89)
      includes material from BCL scrapbook 14 E
      American Sewing Machine Company
      Domestic Sewing Machine Company
      Grover and Baker
      Household Sewing Machine Company
      Howe
      New Home Sewing Machine Company
      Singer Manufacturing Company (Bird calendars,"Costumes of All Nations" series, miscellaneous)
      Wheeler and Wilson Manufacturing Company
      Willcox and Gibbs Sewing Machine Company
      Miscellaneous companies
    - Sports, Toys, and Games (Offsite-box 90)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 15 & 15 A
      Sports:
      Archery
      Baseball
      Basketball
      Billiards
      Boxing and wrestling
      Camping
      Firearms
      Manufacturers (Colt, Remington, Smith & Wesson, Winchester)
      Shot and gunpowder
      Football
      Golf
      Gymnasiums/physical culture/exercise
      Hockey
      Horse racing and riding
    - Sports, Toys, and Games (Offsite-box 91)
      Sports, continued:
      Olympic games
      Rowing
      Skating (see: THEATRICAL ENTERPRISES)
      Tennis
      Toys and games:
      Board games
      Card games
      Carriages, wagons, velocipedes, etc.
      Puzzles
      Toy Merchants and manufacturers (F.A.O. Schwarz, miscellaneous)
    - Stationery and Valentines (Offsite-box 92)
      including material from BCL scrapbooks 15 B-C
      Bookplates
      Bookstraps
      Business Cards
      Calligraphers and engrossers
      Copy presses and machines
      Equipment, miscellaneous
      Envelopes
      Greeting Cards
      Birthday
      Christmas
    - Stationery and Valentines (Offsite-box 93)
      Easter
      New Year's
      Thanksgiving
      Valentines Globes
      Ink, ink stands, writing fluids
      Maps
    - Stationery and Valentines (Offsite-box 94)
      Monograms
      Pencils
      Dixon's
      Eagles Pencil Company Pencil sharpeners
      Pens
      Nibs
      Gum Playing Cards
      Postcards
      Scrap
      Seals and stickers and decals
      Trade cards – samples
      Typewriter accessories
      Typewriters
    - Stationery and Valentines (Offsite-box 95)
      Visiting cards
      Card printers
      Card samples
      Wedding announcements and invitations
      Writing tablets
      Youle Collection of visiting cards and announcements
    - Stoves, Furnaces, and Ranges (Offsite-box 96)
      including material from BCL scrapbooks 15 D-E
      Ash sifters, screens, and cans
      Fuel companies (see also: HOUSEHOLD, Lighting, for gas companies)
      Furnaces and boilers
      Grates and fenders
      Polishes (see: HOUSEHOLD, Polishes, Stove)
      Radiators
      Stove manufacturers
      A-Z manufacturers
    - Stoves, Furnaces, and Ranges (Offsite-box 97)
      Adams and Westlake
      Backus
      Barstow
      Blodgett
      Burdett Smith
      Burtis, Graff & Rice
      Bussey McLeod & Co.
      Doyle "Boss" American
      Excelsior "Charter Oak"
      Giles "Aldine"
      Hull & Grippen
      James & Cornell
      Monitor Oil Stove Co.
      Peckham Perry
      Phillips & Clark "Andes"
      Ransom Stove Works
      Rathbone, Sard & Co.
      Smith & Anthony
      Smith & Sherman "Olmsted's Patent"
      Van Wormer "American" "Astral"
      Weir Stove Co. "Glenwood"
      Wilson
      Stove retailers
      Water heaters
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 98)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 16 A-M
      Aquariums
      Benefit events
      Circuses
      Barnum
      Big Apple
      Buffalo Bill Cody
      Forepaugh
      Ringling Brothers
      Comedy
      Curiosities and wonders
      Anatomical museums
      Barnum's American Museum
      Tom Thumb
      Miscellaneous Dance
      Fairs and expositions (filed chronologically)
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 99)
      Fairs and Expositions (filed chronologically)
      American Institute of the City of New York, 1850s
      U.S. Sanitary Commission, 1864-65
      Great Central Fair, Philadelphia
      Metropolitan Fair, New York Centennial Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876
      World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893
      Pan-American Exposition, Buffalo, 1901
      Louisiana Purchase Exposition, St. Louis, 1904
      Jamestown Ter-centennial Exposition, 1907
      Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, 1915
      Century of Progress International Exposition, Chicago, 1933-34
      New York World's Fair, 1939-40
      New York World's Fair, 1964
      Commemorative (local history) celebrations
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 100)
      Lectures and readings
      Minstrel shows
      Motion pictures
      A-Z movie titles
      Theatres
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 101)
      Music
      Concerts and musical programs
      Importers and manufacturers
      Music boxes and phonographs
      Opera
      Pianos and organs
      Beatty
      Decker Brothers
      Emerson Piano Co.
      Estey
      Haines Brothers
      Peek & Son
      Piercy & Co.
      Sohmer
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 102)
      Pianos and Organs
      Steinway
      Sterling
      Western Cottage
      Wilcox & White
      Publishers, binders and sellers
      Teachers and performers
      Violins
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 103)
      Radio
      Repairs
      Sets
      Skating
      Television
      Broadcast networks
      Cable networks
      Cameras and equipment
      Program guides
      Public television
      Trade literature
      Transmission
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 104)
      Theatre
      1800-1900
      1900-1950
      1950- Theatre history cards
      Ticket envelopes and stubs
      Vaudeville
      Venues
      Academy of Music
      Castle Garden
      Hippodromes
      Madison Square Garden
      Madison Square Theatre
      Manhattan Beach (see: HOTELS, New York City)
      Radio City Music Hall
      Miscellaneou
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 140, Box 105)
      Cards and tags
      Allen & Ginter (Loose cards)
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 106)
      Allen & Ginter - Album tickets
      Album of Worlds Racers
      Birds of America album
      Birds of the Tropics album
      Celebrated American Indian Chiefs album
      City Flag Album
      Fifty Decorations of the Principal Orders of Knighthood and Chivalry album
      Game Birds of America album
      General Government & State Capitol Buildings album
      Napoleon album
      Our Navy album Smokeland album Worlds Inventors album
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 107)
      American Tobacco
      Anargyros
      Buchner
      Consolidated Cigarette
      Duke
      Costumes of All Nations album
      Heroes of the Civil War album
      Postage Stamp Album
      Shadows album
      Sporting Girls album covers
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 108)
      Gail & Ax
      Goodwin
      Hall
      Imperial Tobacco
      Kimball
      Kinney
      Album 1: Queens of the World
      Album 5: Natural History
      Loose cards
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 109)
      Cards and Tags
      Lorillard
      Mayo & Brother
      National Tobacco Works
      Old Dominion
      Miscellaneous brands
      Premium redemption catalog
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 110)
      Chewing tobacco manufacturers
      Jackson Cigar band printers
      Cigar box label printers
      Boyd & Co
      Harris
      Heppenheimer
      Howell & Co
      Johns & Co
      Schwencke
      Witsch & Schmitt
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 111)
      Cigar box manufacturers
      Cigar manufacturers
      Cigarette manufacturers
      Cross-Cut
      Marburg Brothers
      Reynolds
      Cigarette papers
      Cigarette taxes and stamps
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 112)
      Smoking tobacco manufacturers
      Blackwell
      Anti-tobacco material
      Pipes
      Retail merchants
      Sales receipts and invoices
      Tobacco habit cures
      Tobacco substitutes
      Wholesale merchants and distributors
      Miscellaneous material related to tobacco
    - Toilet Article and Beauty Aids (Offsite-box 113)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 18-18A
      Colognes and perfumes
      Austen's
      Caswell, Massey & Co.
      Hoyt's
      Murray & Lanman's
      Rimmel
      Tappan
      Wenck
      A-Z Miscellaneous Face care
      Booklets
      Creams, balms, lotions
    - Toilet Article and Beauty Aids (Offsite-box 114)
      Face powder
      Pozzoni's
      Miscellaneous Makeup
      Hair care
      Barbers, salons, and hair dressers
      Combs, pins, brushes
      Dyes, bleaches and color restorers
      Renewers, tonics, and growth products
      Shampoos
      Styling lotions and products
      Wigs and hairpieces
      Nail care
      Shaving and hair removal
      Spas
      Tattooing
    - Toilet Article and Beauty Aids (Offsite-box 115)
      Soap
      Babbitt's
      Buchan's
      Colgate
      Dobbin's
      Fairbank's Fairy
      Larkin's
      Lautz Brothers
      Palmer's
      Miscellaneous Tooth care
      Breath perfumes
      Mouthwash
      Tooth Pastes and powders
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 116)
      includes material from BCL scrapbooks 19 & 19 A-G
      Automobiles
      Busses and coaches
      Parking
      Taxis and limousines
      Trucks
      Auto Miscellaneous
      Aviation
      Balloon flight
      Collectible cards of military aircraft
      Commercial airlines
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 117)
      Commercial airlines: foreign and U.S.
      American Airlines
      Institute of Aeronautical Science
      Wings Club
      Aviation Miscellaneous
      Bicycles: Clubs, tours and exhibitions; Literature; Manufacturers A-Z; Pope Manufacturing Co.; Maps, guides and road books; Sales agents
      Velocipedes
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 118)
      Bridges
      Brooklyn Bridge: Opening, Miscellaneous
      Canals: Erie, Miscellaneous
      Carriages: Accessories and care; Hacks, stages, and post chaises; Hearses (see: UNDERTAKERS); Livery and boarding stables; Manufacturers in New York State, Pennsylvania, and other. Saddles, etc. (see: LEATHER GOODS); Miscellaneous
      Express Companies/freight forwarders
      American Express
      Freight receipts (all modes)
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 119)
      Railroads
      Equipment manufacturers
      Grand Central Station
      Lines: Amtrak; Chicago & Rock Island; Midwestern US miscellaneous; New England miscellaneous; New Haven Railroad; New Jersey miscellaneous; Pennsylvania Railroad; Southern US miscellaneous; Western US miscellaneous
      New York State lines: Long Island Railroad; Metro-North; New York Central; Miscellaneous
      New York City: Elevated lines; Subway lines; Subway tickets; Surface and excursion lines
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 120)
      Stock certificates (filed by state of incorporation):
      Delaware
      Georgia
      Illinois
      Indiana
      New York
      Pennsylvania
      Vermont
      West Virginia
      Canada
      Unidentified locations
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 121)
      Roads and turnpikes: Maps; miscellaneous
      Ships and boats: Builders and furnishers (see also: HARDWARE Mathematical instruments); Central/South American lines; Ferries; Great Lakes/St. Lawrence lines
      Hudson River lines: Hudson River Day Line; miscellaneous
      Long Island/Staten Island lines
      New England lines
      New Jersey lines
      New York City day excursions
      Sailors
      Towboats
      Transatlantic lines: Cunard; Guion; Holland America; Inman; National; State; White Star; miscellaneous
    - United States Government (Offsite-box 122)
      Inlcudes material from BCL scrapbooks 20 A-B Celebrations:
      Cleveland, Grover
      Clinton, George
      Lafayette
      Roosevelt, Theodore
      Washington, George
      Censuses
      Lawyers
      Political parties: Democrats, Republicans, Whigs, miscellaneous
      Politics:
      Campaigns, miscellaneous
      Court and attorney general campaigns
      New Jersey campaigns New York City campaigns-Seth Low, miscellaneous New York State campaigns
      Presidential campaigns:
      1840,1856,1860,1864,1868,1872,1876,1880,1884,1888,1892,1896,1908,1912,1924,1928,1936,1940, 1948,1952,1984,1988,1992,1996
      Post Office and Stamps
      Suffrage movement
    - Undertakers (Offsite-box 123)
      Includes material from BCL scrapbook 20
      Burial invoices and receipts
      Cemeteries
      Grave markers and burial vaults
      Funeral, burial, and mourning goods suppliers
      Funeral invitations
      Hearses
      Memorial cards Grant, Ulysses Harrison, William H. Lincoln, Abraham Miscellaneous
      Mourning stationery
    - Warehouses (Offsite-box 123)